ici hair lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners
mr dasgupta i want to now speak about
how our lives have changed you know you
began this chat by saying it is so
unusual
would we have thought that we will chat
with you connecting from your home
uh you know remotely until recently we
used to meet
face to face to speak now this has meant
a big leap in digitalization which means
relying on uh you know relying on
internet relying on infotech along with
it comes cyber risk
so just how are you approaching it
as a managing director of a company and
what does this mean in terms of
insurance
can you actually ensure cyber risk
so let me i'll i'll you know talk about
the cyber disaster but
let me step back a bit and talk about uh
what we are seeing overall right
uh one is uh clearly a behavior shift in
our customers
uh in the past people you know were
comfortable with
uh some amount of physical services
people were comfortable with
interacting physically with people now
during the covert period we
saw a preference for digital we saw a
preference for contactless
we also saw organizations uh reorganize
themselves in terms of you know people
working from home etc
all of these are in our mind uh changes
for
uh the future as well um this is not
just an episodic change
we believe this will transform the way
we uh you know
provide our customers with uh services
going ahead and the way we continue to
operate as an organization
so let me just spend two minutes on the
on the customer just to give you
a couple of examples on the health side
since we discussed health one of the
things that we
uh decided during the pandemic was to
allow two things one was the health so
you can do a doctor consult
uh on the app uh which was not in
a in a sense a service that we were
offering it was it was
you know it was a paid service for some
customers but even this period we opened
up to all our customers
we've tremendous attraction and the
positivity around that
that service feature now going ahead we
will not uh continue
with it of course we'll continue with it
because it's a positive for our
customers
second thing that we did was insurance
traditionally pays for hospitalization
claims right so you have to go to the
hospital be there for 24 hours
we started providing home-based care on
a cashless basis
if you reach out to us our service
providers we didn't want to do it on a
reimbursement basis because of
fraud risk but if you reach out to us we
will provide you a cashless service at
home
and customers are very happy with it
because who wants to go to a hospital
when you know there's a pandemic will
this continue we believe this will
continue
so these are just giving a couple of
examples of how we believe
customer uh you know proposition will
change and we as an industry as an
insurance industry need to also change
to service our customers the second
point that you made about
cyber you know traditionally as
insurance companies or any companies
we used to think about the cyber risk in
terms of to mitigate the cyber risk we
used to think a lot about the perimeter
security
uh once people come inside the
organization how strong is our firewall
how their monitoring mechanism
uh you know what is our threat uh you
know the alarm system etc
but it was all within the organization
boundaries
now suddenly people are working from
home so you have to completely
re-architect your
cyber security architecture to thinking
about the end point security as well
and increasingly will be hybrid some
people will be in office some people
will be in
at home uh and i think that's really
been another challenge in terms of
re-architecture are
architecting our uh security
architecture and
increasingly we believe as an insurance
company that the cyber risk is going to
become a
larger and larger component of the risk
that all of us in
corporate india have and we need to
protect for those
what has been the ability for you to
process claims remotely i mean until now
perhaps uh
you did many of your claims remotely say
uh
you know an accident insurance cover a
vehicle insurance cover
i guess all of you were already prepared
to do it remotely
but now have you been able to migrate
everything to remote
uh have there been people disputing your
assessment of the
uh you know damage vis-a-vis theirs
is remote really working both in terms
of selling insurance
and settling claims you know uh
we are big believers in digital and
giving power to the customer power in
the hands of the customer and you know
do it yourself diy is really we believe
very empowering
and our experiences whenever customers
process or initiate the process on their
own
we see much less dissonance so be it in
terms of issuing policies
uh digitally you know if you have the
email
you know which mostly you do i mean in
gi
industry you don't have kyc but
customers are willing to share that with
you
uh so if you have the email your policy
is available to you immediately you take
a print out in a physical version where
you send it through
you know posterior there will be that
eight nine person that will you know
you'll have rt
written from origin etc you'll not the
the the policy document won't reach
even at a simplistic level it is better
for the customer
coming to your bigger point on claims
look uh
all of us had that capability at least
we had pioneered this uh you know
virtual
inspection for uh or you know for uh
auto damages so
uh you took a you you know on your app
you could take a
video it will stream real time live into
our claims hubs
our claims manager would look at it and
give the authorization
that was roughly about 20 25 of our
policies would go through their claims
would go through that process
during the first one or two months of
the pandemic hundred percent went
through that process
because there was no other choice right
you couldn't uh do anything physically
even as we speak uh that number is you
know ranging
somewhere around 50 to 60 percent oh
when people option of going to
a physical inspection process i see you
know significant increase in terms of
the number of people who are
preferring a virtual inspection rather
than a physical inspection and our and
our complaint numbers and the
dissonances are much less actually oh
okay okay actually that leads very
nicely to my last question you know when
i spoke with
other company heads like yourselves
about what has pandemic left behind on
the hr front
there was one gentleman who said trust
you know even after the pandemic goes
i will trust my employees more until
before the pandemic
we had to have them in line of sight
people worked only when you saw them
working
but now you trust what is your
experience
do you think this trust factor you just
said that you know customer
disputing your claims are actually
falling
so do you think trust is something we
have gained from the pandemic
you know i can my personal belief i
don't know who
told you that about the employee force
uh that is completely my
experience as well the entire management
by wandering about by overseeing someone
looking over someone's shoulder
is probably thing of the past and one of
the
biggest gains that we've had because of
this new way of working of hybrid
working is i believe one
is the trust factor and organizations
have to gear up to
manage uh you know through trust
obviously you trust by but verify you
look at what's happening but you
implicitly trust your team in terms of
doing their job and our experience has
been tremendously positive
in terms of how we've seen our employees
step up
on this factor and the second i would
argue is a big positive is uh
i think this this whole flexi working uh
or
digital working actually flattens the
organization and is more inclusive
it's more inclusive in the sense that
today for uh you know in let's say
corporate office meetings in the past
not everyone would travel from
everywhere
part of the country right if it's just a
one-hour meeting someone would say okay
you know
let it be uh today every stakeholder
who's relevant for that meeting can join
without any effort that's right we can
do large town halls with people in you
know across the country at a
you know at the top of our hat right so
i think there's a lot of positives in
terms of inclusivity and flattening of
the organization
which i believe culturally can be very
positive for organizations that
continue to adapt uh you know or adopt
this way of working
[Music]
ici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards honoring
the new age risk management
practitioners